Hello friends, Namaskar, I heartily welcome all of you to SM Kisi Shaina.
So friends, finally the
biggest festival of the stock market has
started here.  And what is that thing
?  Yes, quarter numbers, we are currently
in quarter four.  So the results of Quarter 4 have
started coming to us here.
That had already started two-three days ago.
But from today the actual
atmosphere has started here.  Because the
beginning has already been made here with the numbers of big companies.
So TCS numbers are
out in front of us.  You all know the giant company of NFT 50.
It leads the IT sector of its own sector.
All of you know it.  So TCS
numbers have come before us here.  And
we will read these numbers.  Along with reading the numbers,
what other
commentary has the management given here and what
points has it put forward.  Has dividend been paid or
not?  TCS
gives dividend every quarter.  So
how much have you given at this time?  How much was expected?
How much did you actually get?
What have they talked about AI?
We will cover everything here.  So let's
start here.  First of all, if
we look, you can see that these are the
numbers for March 2025.  These are the numbers as of December 25th,
meaning Quarter 3 numbers and here are our
current Quarter 4 numbers as of March 26th.
So let's talk about the top line which we
call sales.  Can you check how much it is?
TCS used to earn sales revenue of Rs 64,479 crore
in the same quarter a year ago.  How much did it become in March?
70,698
crores.  So a very big and very good jump is being
seen yearly.  Three months ago
in December, this figure was around Rs 67,000 crore,
which has now crossed Rs 70,000 crore.
So quarterly and yearly we can say that a
good jump has been seen in sales revenue.
But if we talk about it here, then to do so much, we have to
spend money
also.  So how much does it cost?
You can see.  47 499 48 818 and at this time
so what will you get if you subtract expenses from income
?  Will there be profit or loss?  So
brother, there is no scope for loss.  TCS
is there.  Yes, it is possible that the profit may fluctuate.
So if we talk about operating level normal profit,
you can see that it was Rs 16,980
crore and now it has become Rs 19,278 crore.  And
3 months ago in quarter 3 it was Rs 18,269
crore.  This is Rs 19,276 crore.  Meaning,
if we talk about quarterly and yearly, then
numerically we are seeing a jump in both.
But if we
talk about it here then it becomes a normal thing.
After that there will be multiple adjustments.
Tax will have to be paid and then finally comes the
Net Profit After Tax (NPAT).  So
how much is this final profit?  So 1 year ago it was worth Rs
93 crores.  That has become Rs 13784
crore.  And 3 months ago it was Rs 10,720 crore
which has now become Rs 13,784 crore.  So, as the
Net Profit After Tax (NPAT)
increases, EPS will also increase accordingly.
So you can see the EPS,
EPS of 33.79, EPS of 37.92, EPS of
29.45, EPS of 37.92,
so overall if we talk here then
numerically normally the company has
shown good performance here quarterly, yearly at least.  Ok?  It became
normal.  Actually, we will
compare it with the estimate and
see it here.  He will come after some time.
What about dividends?  If we look at it at all times, the
company gives dividend to the shareholders of TCS whether it is quarter one, two, three or four.  So at this
time the company has given the final dividend.
How much?  31 shares.  Meaning at ₹31 per share.
But some people may get angry here.
Because many people were expecting
it to be above 40.  Let's say there can be at
least a dividend of 40.
Actually only 31 are visible.
I am just
putting it for comparison.  Ok?  So
you can note this one point.  Now friends let us come to the
actual versus estimated number,
how much was estimated and how much actually came.
So you can see let's
start with estimated revenue.  The estimate
was that it should
come to 69494 crores but actually we
saw that it came to 70000 plus, what does it mean,
what is the status, the revenue has at least been
beaten, it is better than the estimate, then
if we talk about PAT net profit after
tax, the expectation was 135000 crores, here
how much is 13718 crores, it has been slightly beaten,
but let's do it, then
if we talk about EBITDA margin, from 25.2 to 25.4, so
let's say it is inline, 20 to 25.3 is in between that.
If we talk about the big
deals, the total contract value that can be seen will be
around Rs 10 billion.
This is 12 billion.  So, this is also good.
And the last thing which is very
important is what is the CC revenue growth
?  Quarter on quarter.  Ok?
According to the consensus currency.  Ok?
We will not consider the appreciation that is taking place in the Coke Dollar.
So the estimate was 1 to 1.5%.
Ok?  In between that comes the
1.2 inline.  So
how were the actual numbers as per the estimates?  So
I have placed this data before you all.
Then what about the client edition.  Ok?
Big clients: I
told you earlier also that your clients will increase.   If
big names join, then there are
chances of your revenue top line improving.
So TCS added two clients in the
100 million plus bracket.  Ok?  And
how many have happened?  I have 66 clients
brother.  Meaning these are very big clients.
Just imagine seeing clients with $100 million.
And
how many clients are there in the $50 million plus bracket in total?  139 Currently,
he has added nine more clients here.  So
if we talk about the overall client base, the performance of big
clients and medium sized clients is quite
good.
Now friends let us come to one of the most important
points.  Artificial Intelligence
AI, this is the thing that has been troubling everyone.
So if we look at AI,
TCS is doing well.
Our IT companies are not doing that much work,
but still if you
look at the work they are doing, you can see that
if we talk about annualized AI led revenue, it has
crossed $2.3 billion
in quarter 4, which
if we talk about the previous quarter, was $1.8 billion.  So let
us say that the work that is going on related to AI was
earlier 1.8 and now it has gone up to 2.3.
So gradually, things related to AI are also being
seen.  But
if we talk about it here, then the
performance of TCS related to the Indian market has become
very bad.  This means that there is a
decline of 23% in the income generated from India.  Do
you know from where TCS earns the most
?  From America, from Europe.  This is where he
makes the most money.
India is not such a big market.
For all the IT companies.  So
here a decline of 23% is visible.
If we talk about Asia Pacific, a
decline of 5% is visible here too.
And along with that, the company's
communication and media segment is
also seeing a decline, somewhere
around 0.4 to 2.1% in CC terms in
constant currency terms.  So
we are also seeing some negative points.
If we talk about it,
you know that any company is
run by senior level management.  So
if we talk about senior level exit here,
which we also call attrition rate here, it is
seen to be up to 16%.  Meaning, in
big BPs and above all, the
people we see in management,
16% of the top tier people are
seen leaving the company.  Ok?
Replacement is also available.  But this is an
important data that we are seeing coming before us.
Now if we talk about
one such thing due to which
we are facing problems, then
that is uncertainty.  And
if we talk about TCS, if we talk about management, then
he again said that
if we talk about global macro level economy, the
uncertainty that has been created can continue in future also.
And due to this thing the
company may face problems.  Because what can their
clients do due to this uncertainty
?  You may delay decision making.
So, this is the biggest problem that
TCS and all our other IT companies are
facing.  First of all, Trump bothered me by asking,
what exactly is Trump's policy?  That IT Hire Act regarding foreign IT companies,
brother, remained aside.
Things related to that war started happening.
So people were troubled because of this thing.
Then the AI ​​thing started.  So, right now
things like war are also going on.
So what is the problem due to this thing
?  Yes, it depends on how much the client will spend.   There is
no rate cut either.  So if there is a rate cut then the
clients end up spending more money.
If they do this, they will
get more business.  So this cycle remains.  So for
now we can say that friends, the
spending that is going on here is a bit like what
you mean, we are seeing a tough scenario.
And this is
not just a matter of now, these things have been seen continuing even before this.
So what next?  Now what?  So at least
TCS has put forward its numbers.
Ultimately the stock market remains supreme.
So how did the market like TCS numbers?
This will definitely be an interesting part to watch tomorrow.
But if we talk about it here,
friends, then we can also focus on the American market.
Because you know that
Wipro and Infosys, no doubt, are
not as big companies as TCS.  Ok?  But still it
comes around the same i.e. in the large cap segment only.  So their ADRs
trade in the American market.  So let
us focus on these.   For example, if we
talk about Wipro's ADR,
you can see that it is down by 1/4%.  Ok?   It has just
begun.  I am telling you accordingly.
And a
decline of 2.5% has been seen in the ADR of Infosys here.
Ok?  So this is the
reaction we are seeing after the TCS numbers came out.  The
original reaction will be known only tomorrow.
When the actual
opening of TCS shares will happen then it will be known how the
market has liked the overall performance.  So
okay friends, I hope you found the video
helpful.  I have
tried to present all the things before you in as simple language as possible along with all the examples.  So if
you want, you can like and share the video.
And you can also leave your comments
in the comment section.  How do you like
TCS numbers?  Liked it, didn't like it.
Do you think that tomorrow we will see green or red color in TCS shares
?  You
can definitely mention this point in the comment section.  So friends,
see you in the next video.  Until then, bye bye.